在你左边
On your left.
左边  我知道了
Uh-huh, on my left. Got it.
别说了  你别说了
Don't say it! Don't you say it!
在你左边
On your left!
怎么还说
Come on!
需要叫医生吗
Need a medic?
我需要换肺了
I need a new set of lungs.
你刚刚半小时跑了快十三英里
Dude, you just ran like thirteen miles in thirty minutes.
起得晚就要多跑跑
I guess I got a late start.
是吗
Oh, really?
你真不害臊
You should be ashamed of yourself.
再跑一圈去吧
You should take another lap.
你已经跑完了吗
Did you just take it?
就当你又跑了一圈吧
I assumed you just took it.
你是哪个部队的
What unit are you with?
五十八师  空降救援部队
Fifty-eighth, Para-rescue.
但是我现在在退伍军人服务处工作  山姆·威尔逊
But now I'm working down at the V.A. Sam Wilson.
史蒂夫·罗杰斯
Steve Rogers.
我能猜得出来
I kind of put that together.
解冻之后回家一看
Must have freaked you out,
是不是把你吓坏了
coming home after the whole defrosting thing.
是得慢慢习惯
It takes some getting used to.
很高兴见到你  山姆
It's good to meet you, Sam.
是床的问题  对吧
It's your bed, right?
什么
What's that?
你的床  太软了
Your bed, it's too soft.
我还服役的时候  躺在地上就可以睡觉
When I was over there I sleep on the ground
拿石头当枕头  像原始人一样
and used rock for pillows, like a caveman.
我现在回家了  躺在床上  就像
Now I'm home, lying in my bed, and it's like...
躺在棉花糖上
Lying on a marshmallow.
感觉自己快要沉到地上去了
I feel like I'm gonna sink right to the floor.
多久
How long?
外出执勤两次
Two tours.
你肯定很怀念以前的生活
You must miss the good old days, huh?
其实现在还好
Well, things aren't so bad.
吃的强多了  以前只会煮
Food's a lot better, we used to boil everything.
小儿麻痹能治愈了  互联网  真厉害
No polio is good. Internet, so helpful.
我在网上看好多东西  想跟上时代
I've been reading that a lot trying to catch up.
马文·盖伊  1972年的专辑《黑手煞星》
Marvin Gaye, 1972, "Trouble Man" soundtrack.
你错过的事  这专辑里面都有
Everything you've missed jammed into one album.
我要记在备忘录里面
I'll put it on the list.
我爱露西  电视剧
登月
柏林墙  建立和拆毁
乔布斯  苹果
迪斯科
泰国菜
星际大战\迷航
涅槃乐队
洛奇  洛奇2
黑手煞星
有任务  立即动身  路边见
山姆  有任务了  谢谢你跟我一起跑步
Alright, Sam, duty calls. Thanks for the run.
如果你那也叫跑步的话
If that's what you wanna call running.
至于这么说吗
Oh, that's how it is?
-至于  -好吧
- Oh, that's how it is. - Okay.
你哪天想去退伍军人服务处
Any time you wanna stop by the V.A,
帮我在前台姑娘那涨涨人气
make me look awesome in front of the girl at the front desk,
提前通知我一声
just let me know.
记下了
I'll keep it in mind.
好
Okay.
小伙子们
Hey, fellas.
谁知道怎么去史密森尼博物馆
Either one of you know where the Smithsonian is?
我要去接一块化石
I'm here to pick up a fossil.
真好笑
It's hilarious.
你好
How you doing?
不是哪儿都能跑去的
You can't run everywhere.
对啊
No, you can't.
印度洋
纬度  16N 55' 12.06"  经度  73N 56' 7.09"
目标是一个移动卫星发射云台
The target is a mobile satellite launch platform:
雷姆利亚星号
The Lemurian Star.
93分钟之前  海盗登船时
It was sending up their last payload
他们正在发射最后一颗卫星
when pirates took them, ninety-three minutes ago.
情况紧急
占领状态
对方有什么要求
Any demands?
十五亿
A billion and a half.
要这么多
Why so steep?
因为是神盾局的船
Because it S.H.I.E.L.D's.
所以不是偏离航向  是非法入侵
So it's not off course, it's trespass.
他们肯定有理由
I'm sure they have a good reason.
我讨厌总给弗瑞擦屁股
You know, I'm getting a little tired of being Fury's janitor.
放轻松  没那么复杂
Relax, it's not that complicated.
有多少海盗
How many pirates?
二十五个
Twenty-five,
顶级雇佣兵  由乔治·巴托克领导
top mercs, led by this guy. Georges Batroc.
前对外安全总局行动部门官员
Ex-DGSE, Action Division.
国际刑警"红色通告"上的头号通缉犯
He's at the top of Interpol's "Red notice".
他在被法国遣散之前
Before the French demobilized him,
执行过三十六次暗杀任务
he had thirty-six kill missions.
他就擅长大开杀戒
This guy's got a rep for maximum casualties.
人质呢
Hostages?
大部分是技术人员  一个官员  贾斯珀·西特韦尔
Uh... mostly techs. One officer, Jasper Sitwell.
个人档案
都在厨房
They're in the galley.
西特韦尔在发射船上做什么
What's Sitwell doing on a launch ship?
好了  我扫荡甲板  然后找巴托克
Alright, I'm gonna sweep the deck and find Batroc.
娜塔莎  你关掉引擎等待命令
Nat, you'll kill the engines and wait for instructions.
朗姆洛  你负责船尾的人  找出人质
Rumlow, you sweep aft,find the hostages,
带他们上救生艇  救出他们  出发
get them to life pods. Get 'em out. Let's go.
突击队  听到了吧  准备行动
S.T.R.I.K.E, you heard the Captain. Gear up!
七频道确认安全
Secure channel seven.
确认
Seven secure.
周六晚上找乐子了吗
You do anything fun Saturday night?
以前跟我一起组队的家伙都死光了
Well, all the guys from my barbershop quartet are dead,
所以  没找成
so...no, not really.
队长  马上进入跳伞区域
Coming up by the drop zone, Cap.
你约统计部的克里斯汀试试
You know, if you ask Kristen out, from Statistics,
她很可能同意呢
she'll probably say yes.
所以我才不约
That's why I don't ask.
太害羞还是太害怕
Too shy or too scared?
是太忙
Too busy!
他戴降落伞了吗
Was he wearing a parachute?
没有  没戴
No. No, he wasn't.
不要动  不要动
Don't move! Don't move!
谢谢
Thanks.
不用谢  没了我你可怎么活
Yeah. You seemed pretty helpless without me.
住你对门的护士怎么样
What about the nurse that lives across the hall from you?
她长得挺漂亮的
She seems kind of nice.
先搞定引擎室  再说约会的事
Secure the engine room, then find me a date.
我能一心多用
I'm multitasking.
我跟巴托克说了  想要神盾局付钱
I said to Batroc, if we want SHIELD to pay,
就得杀几个人给他们看
we have to start sending bodies now!
我就准备杀一个
I have a bullet for someone.
你想吃枪子吗
You want a bullet in your head?!
收好腿  想吃枪子吗
Move that leg. Want a bullet in your head?
我不喜欢等
I don't like waiting.
打给杜兰德
Call Durand.
救援一来就开船
I want the ship ready to go as soon as the rescue arrives.
是  巴托克
Yes, Batroc.
杜兰德  启动引擎
Durand. Start the engine.
好
Okay.
你好  水手
Hey, sailor.
闭嘴  怎么回事  想当英雄吗
Shut up. What is it? Want to be a hero?
我可等够了
Well, I've waited long enough.
找巴托克
Hey, look for Batroc.
两分钟内不回话  我就开始杀人了
If I do not hear in two minutes, I'll start to kill them!
好  我去找他
Okay. I'll find him!
两分钟
Two minutes.
巴托克  神盾局的无线电不回应
Radio silence from S.H.I.E.L.D, Batroc.
目标确认
Targets acquired.
突击队就位
S.T.R.I.K.E in position.
娜塔莎  你那边情况如何
Natasha, what's your status?
娜塔莎  汇报情况
Status, Natasha?
等等
Hang on!
引擎室搞定
Engine room secure.
时间到了  谁想先死
Time's up. Who wants to die first?
你  抓那个女的
Hey, you! Take the girl.
听我命令
On my mark.
三  二  一
Three. Two. One.
我说过  神盾局从不谈判
I told you, S.H.I.E.L.D doesn't negotiate.
喂  巴托克
Hello? Batroc,
那边没回应  联系不上
the line is dead. I lost contact with them.
小心
Look out!
人质正在撤退
Hostages enroute to extraction.
罗曼诺夫没有来碰头  队长
Romanoff missed the rendezvous point, Captain.
敌方仍在反抗
Hostiles are still in play.
娜塔莎  巴托克逃了
Natasha, Batroc's on the move.
绕到朗姆洛后面去保护人质
Circle back to Rumlow and protect the hostages.
娜塔莎
Natasha!
你不是徒有其表吧
I thought that you were more than just a shield.
来试试看
Let's find out.
真尴尬
Well, this is awkward.
你干什么
What are you doing?
备份硬盘数据
Backing up the hard drive.
这是个好习惯
It's a good habit to get into.
朗姆洛需要你帮忙
Rumlow needed your help.
你在这干什么呢
What the hell are you doing here?
你在挽救神盾局情报
You're saving S.H.I.E.L.D intel.
尽可能多地救下来
Whatever I can get my hands on.
我们的任务是救人质
Our mission is to rescue hostages.
那是你的任务
No. That's your mission.
你完成的很出色
And you've done it beautifully.
你威胁到整个行动了
You just jeopardized this whole operation.
你太夸张了吧
I think that's overstating things.
好吧  这次怪我
Okay. That one's on me.
就是怪你
You damn right.
神盾局总部
纬度  38N 53' 33.78"  经度  77S 3' 38.91"
你就只会满嘴谎话  是不是
You just can't stop yourself from lying, can you?
我没说谎  罗曼诺夫特工的任务和你不同
I didn't lie. Agent Romanoff had a different mission than yours.
你就没有义务跟我分享信息吗
Which you didn't feel obliged to share.
我没有义务做任何事
I'm not obliged to do anything.
人质可能全部丧命的  尼克
Those hostages could've died, Nick.
所以我派了有史以来最棒的士兵
I sent the greatest soldier in history
去救他们的命
to make sure that didn't happen.
士兵需要相互信任  军队靠的也是信任
Soldiers trust each other, that's what makes it an army.
而不是放大伙乱开枪
Not a bunch of guys running around and shooting guns.
上次我信任了别人
The last time I trusted someone,
丢了只眼睛
I lost an eye.
我不想给你分配你不想做的任务
Look, I didn't want you doing anything you weren't comfortable with.
罗曼诺夫特工没有不想做的事
Agent Romanoff is comfortable with everything.
手下的人各行其是
I can't lead a mission
你叫我怎么带队执行任务
when the people I'm leading have missions of their owns.
那叫各司其职
It's called compartmentalization.
没人泄露秘密  因为大家都只知道一部分
Nobody spills the secrets because nobody knows them all.
除了你
Except you.
你看错我了
You're wrong about me.
我会分享的
I do share.
因为我是大好人
I'm nice like that.
洞察计划舰湾
Insight bay.
罗杰斯队长没有进入洞察计划的权限
Captain Rogers does not have clearance for Project Insight.
拒绝访问
越级授权  尼古拉斯·J·弗瑞局长
Director override, Fury, Nicholas J.
已确认
Confirmed.
以前电梯还放音乐的
You know, they used to play music.
是啊
Yeah.
我爷爷当了40年电梯操作员
My grandfather operated one of these things for forty years.
他工作的大楼挺不错
My granddad worked in a nice building,
小费拿的不少
he got good tips.
他晚上回家
He'd walk home every night,
午餐袋里能有一大卷一块钱
roll of ones stuffed in his lunch bag.
他跟人问好  别人也回应
He'd say "hi", people would say hi back.
后来  世风日下
Time went on, neighborhood got rougher.
他再问好  别人都说  少废话
He'd say "Hi", they'd say, "Keep on steppin'."
他得时刻小心自己的午餐袋
Granddad got to grippin' that lunch bag a little tighter.
他被抢过吗
Did he ever get mugged?
每周都有小混混问他  袋子里有啥
Every week some punk would say, "What's in the bag?"
他怎么办呢
Well, what did he do?
给他们看看吧
He'd show 'em.
一堆破旧的一块钱  还有把上膛的点22马格南
A bunch of crumpled ones and loaded 0.22 Magnum.
我爷爷喜欢别人  只是不太相信别人
Granddad loved people. But he didn't trust them very much.
是啊  是比马格南大了点
Yeah, I know. They're a little bit bigger than a 0.22.
这是洞察计划
This is Project Insight.
超前三代的直升航母  与定位卫星连线
Three next generation helicarriers synced to a network of targeting satellites.
雷姆利亚星号发射的卫星
Launched from the Lemurian Star.
一旦上了天  就不用降落了
Once we get them in the air they never need to come down.
新的引擎可以持续做亚轨道飞行
Continuous suborbital flight courtesy of our new repulser engines.
斯塔克设计的吗
Stark?
他看了旧的涡轮增压引擎
Well, he had a few suggestions
就给我们提了点建议
once he got an up close look at our old turbines.
这些远距离精准定位武器
These new long range precision guns
一分钟能消灭一千敌人
can eliminate a thousand hostiles a minute.
恐怖分子不需要露面
The satellites can read a terrorist's DNA
卫星就能读取他的DNA
before he steps outside his spider hole.
我们能把许多威胁扼杀在摇篮里
We gonna neutralize a lot of threats before they even happen.
做了坏事的人才该受到惩罚吧
I thought the punishment usually came after the crime.
我们不能等到别人做了坏事
We can't afford to wait that long.
我们是谁
Who's "we"?
纽约的事之后  我说服了世界安全理事会
After New York, I convinced the World Security Council
我们需要量子级的精密威胁分析
we needed a quantum surgeon threat analysis.
这次我们远远地走在前面
For once we're way ahead of the curve.
拿枪指着所有人  你管这个叫保护吗
By holding a gun at everyone on Earth and calling it protection.
我读过战略科学军团的文件
You know, I read those SSR files.
最伟大的一代吗  你们可干过见不得人的事
Greatest generation? You guys did some nasty stuff.
是啊  我们妥协了
Yeah, we compromised.
有时会因为这个夜不能寐
Sometimes in ways that made us not sleep so well.
但我们是为了人民的自由
But we did it so the people could be free.
但这不叫自由  这是恐惧
This isn't freedom, this is fear.
神盾局接受现在的世界  而不是按自己的意愿改变世界
S.H.I.E.L.D takes the world as it is, not as we'd like it to be.
你现在着手那个计划
It's getting damn near pasttime
有点太晚了吧  队长
for you to get with that program, Cap.
所以别抱太大希望
Don't hold your breath.
圣路易精神号
队长  欢迎回来
美国队长
当世的传奇
勇气的象征
国家的象征
A symbol to the nation.
美国队长
当世的传奇
勇气的象征
美国队长
当世的传奇
勇气的象征
世界的英雄
A hero to the world.
美国队长的故事是荣誉
The story of Captain America is one of honor,
勇气和牺牲的故事
bravery and sacrifice.
注射血清前
体重  95磅
身高  5尺4英寸
身体状况不佳未能入伍
Denied enlistment due to poor health,
注射血清后
体重  240磅
身高  6尺2英寸
史蒂夫·罗杰斯被选中参与美国二战时
Steven Rogers was chosen for a program unique
一个独一无二的项目
in the annals of American warfare.
这将他变成史上第一位超级士兵
One that would transform him into the world's first super soldier.
这段珍贵的录影里
In this rare footage,
大家最爱的勇士  美国队长
everyone's favorite warrior, Captain America...
历经了沙场的考验
Battle tested,
美国队长与他的咆哮突击队
Captain America and his Howling Commandos
步步高升
quickly earned their stripes.
他们的任务是瓦解九头蛇
Their mission, taking down Hydra,
纳粹研究危险科技的部门
the Nazi rogue science division.
牺
牲
的
同
志
作为儿时的挚友
Best friends since childhood,
无论在校园里  还是在战场上
Bucky Barnes and Steven Rogers were inseparable
巴基·巴恩斯与史蒂夫·罗杰斯都形影不离
on both school yard and battlefield.
巴恩斯是咆哮突击队中
Barnes is the only Howling Commando
唯一一位为国捐躯的战士
to give his life in service of his country.
那年冬天格外严酷
That was a difficult winter.
佩姬·卡特特工  战略科学军团  纽约  1953年
一场暴风雪将半个营困在了德国境内
A blizzard had trapped half our battalion behind the German line.
史蒂夫  罗杰斯队长
Steve... Captain Rogers,
他成功穿越九头蛇对美军的封锁
he fought his way through a Hydra blockade
突破了进去
that had pinned our allies down for months.
他救了一千多人
He saved over a thousand men,
包括后来
including the man who would...
后来成为我丈夫的这位
who would become my husband as it turned out.
甚至在他死后  史蒂夫也在改变着我的生活
Even after he died, Steve was still changing my life.
你应该为自己骄傲  佩姬
You should be proud of yourself, Peggy.
我活了一辈子
I have lived a life.
唯一的遗憾是你没过上自己的生活
My only regret is that you didn't get to live yours.
怎么了
What is it?
一直以来  我的原则是只做正确的事
For as long as I can remember I just wanted to do what was right.
现在这个原则也动摇了
I guess I'm not quite sure what that is anymore.
我以为自己可以随时回军队
And I thought I could throw myself back in
遵守命令  保家卫国
and follow orders, serve.
可是已经不一样了
It's just not the same.
你老是这么夸张
You're always so dramatic.
是你拯救了世界
Look, you saved the world.
而我们  又给弄得一团糟
We rather...mucked it up.
哪有
You didn't.
我留下来  一半是因为听说你参与创办了神盾局
Knowing that you helped found S.H.I.E.L.D is half the reason I stay.
世界已经变了  我们回不去了
The world has changed and none of us can go back.
我们只能尽力做到最好
All we can do is our best,
而有时  最好的选择就是重新开始
and sometimes the best that we can do is to start over.
佩姬
Peggy.
史蒂夫
Steve?
你还活着  你  你回来了
You're alive! You... you came, you came back.
是啊  佩姬
Yeah, Peggy.
好久不见了
It's been so long.
好久了
So long.
我怎么能离开我的美人
Well, I couldn't leave my best girl.
她还欠我一支舞呢
Not when she owes me a dance.
封闭办公室
Secure office.
打开雷姆利亚星号卫星发射文件
Open Lemurian Star satellite launch file.
拒绝访问
Access denied.
运行解密
Run decryption.
解密失败
Decryption failed.
越级授权  尼古拉斯·J·弗瑞局长
Director override, Fury, Nicholas J.
授权失败  文件全部封存
Override denied. All files sealed.
谁的的命令
On whose authority?
尼古拉斯·J·弗瑞
Fury, Nicholas J.
世界安全理事会
World Security Council.
确认
Confirmed.
如果尼克·弗瑞觉得他的面具男
If Nick Fury thinks he can get us costumed thugs
和突击队能处理他惹的麻烦
and S.T.R.I.K.E commandos to mop-up his mess,
真是大错特错  这个错误不能容忍
he's sadly mistaken. This failure is unacceptable.
鉴于袭击就发生在
Well, considering this attack took place one mile
我国海域一英里外
from my country's sovereign waters,
恐怕这样还不够  我要开听证会
it's a bit more then that. I move for immediate hearing.
我们不需要听证会  需要行动
We don't need hearings, we need action.
理事会的责任是监管神盾局
It's this Council's duty to oversee S.H.I.E.L.D.
这次的问题引出了许多疑问
A breach like this raises serious questions.
比如一个法国海盗
Like how the hell did a French pirate
怎么能光天化日劫持了神盾局的机密军舰
manage to hijack a covert S.H.I.E.L.D vessel in broad daylight?
申明一下  理事
For the record, councilman,
他是阿尔及利亚人
he's Algerian.
需要的话可以画张地图
I can draw a map if it'll help.
感谢你的智慧  皮尔斯部长
I appreciate your wits, Secretary Pierce.
但是理事会
But this council take things
对国际海盗的事是很认真的
like international piracy fairly seriously.
是吗  我倒不在乎
Really? I don't.
我不在乎一船一舰
I don't care about one boat,
我在乎整个舰队
I care about the fleet.
如果理事会遇到点小事
If this council is going to fold a rancor every time
就要把我数落一顿
someone pushes us on the playing field,
是不是也要有人监管我们了
maybe we need someone to oversee us.
部长先生  我们不是说...
Mr. Secretary, nobody is suggesting...
失陪一下
Excuse me.
又有麻烦了吗  部长先生
More trouble, Mr. Secretary?
取决于你怎么定义麻烦
It depends on your definition.
我们办公室只隔了四十层
I work forty floors away
没人劫船你都不肯来吗
and it takes a hijacking for you to visit?
核战爆发我也会来的
Well, a nuclear war would do it too.
忙吗
Busy in there?
用钱都能解决
Nothing some earmarks can't fix.
我是来找你帮忙的
I'm here to ask a favor.
我希望你能组织一次投票
I want you to call for a vote.
洞察计划需要延后
Project Insight has to be delayed.
尼克  你这不是找我帮忙
Nick, that's not a favor,
这需要小组委员会开好长的听证会
that's a subcommittee hearing. A long one.
也许是没什么问题
It could be nothing, probably is nothing.
可我得确保万无一失
I just need time to make sure it's nothing.
如果有问题呢
What if it's something?
那我们都该庆幸
Then we'll both be damn glad
没把直升航母送上天
those Helicarriers aren't in the air.
好吧
Fine.
但你得让钢铁侠参加我侄女的生日派对
But you gotta get Iron Man to stop by my niece's birthday party.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
不是路过  得好好玩会儿
And not just a fly-by, he's got to mingle.
问题是我觉得情况在恶化
The thing is I think it's getting worse.
上周一个警察让我停在路边
A cop pulled me over last week,
他以为我喝醉了
he thought I was drunk.
我急转弯  想躲一个塑料袋
I swerved to miss a plastic bag.
我以为那是简易炸弹
I thought it was an IED.
有些东西留在了那边
Some stuff you leave there,
有些东西需要带回来
other stuff you bring back.
怎么带回来是我们自己的事
It's our job to figure out how to carry it.
是装在箱子里
Is it gonna be in a big suitcase
还是放在钱包里
or in a little man-purse?
取决于你自己
It's up to you.
下周见
I'll see you next week.
这不是跑步小能手吗
Look who it is. The running man.
听到了最后几分钟  讲得真好
Caught the last few minutes. It's pretty intense.
是啊
Yeah, brother,
我们都有一样的问题
we all got the same problems.
愧疚  悔恨
Guilt, regret.
你失去了亲近的人吗
You lose someone?
我的僚机莱利  夜间飞行任务
My wingman, Riley. Fly in the night mission.
标准的空降救援任务
A standard PJ rescue op,
演练过几千次的事了
nothing we hadn't done a thousand times before,
可是一枚火箭弹击中了莱利
till RPG knock Riley's dumb ass out of the sky.
我什么也做不到  只能眼睁睁看着
Nothing I could do. It's like I was up there just to watch.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
那之后
After that,
我纠结了好一阵寻找一个留在那的原因
I had really hard time finding a reason for being over there, you know?
回归正常生活很开心吧
But you're happy now, back in the world?
给我下命令的长官们
Hey, the number of people giving me orders
好像都不在了
is down to about zero.
算是吧  你想退出吗
So, hell, yeah. You thinking about getting out?
我也不知道
No. I don't know.
说实话  我都不知道退出了还能干什么
To be honest, I don't know what I would do with myself if I did.
去终极格斗吗
Ultimate fighting?
我一下子就想到了这个
It's just a great idea off the top of my head.
但说真的  你想干什么都行
But seriously, you could do whatever you want to do.
你喜欢干什么
What makes you happy?
不知道
I don't know.
启动通讯加密程序
Activating communications encryption protocol.
接通安全线路0405
Open secure line zero-four-zero-five.
确认
Confirmed.
我是希尔
This is Hill.
我需要你来华盛顿  情况严重
I need you here in D.C. Deep shadow conditions.
我四小时到
Give me four hours.
给你三小时  完毕
You have three, over.
要查我证件吗
Want to see my lease?
发现骨折
Fracture detected.
建议注射麻醉剂
Recommend anesthetic injection.
附近地区并未部署国会警察
D.C. Metropolice dispatch shows no units in this area.
快离开这
Get me out of here!
动力系统失效
Propulsion systems offline.
那就快他妈重启
Then reboot, damn it!
外壳强度
警告  车窗即将受损
Warning! Window integrity compromised.
是吗
You think?
要多久启动
How long to propulsion?
计算中
Calculating.
车窗强度  31%
Window Integrity thiry-one percent.
准备反制措施
Deploying counter measures.
先等下
Hold that order!
车窗强度  19%
Window Integrity nineteen percent.
-建议启动反制措施  -等等
- Offensive measures advised. - Wait!
车窗强度  1%
Window Integrity one percent.
就是现在
Now!
动力系统已恢复
Propulsion systems now online.
全速前进
Full acceleration, now!
启动直升功能
Initiate vertical takeoff!
飞行系统损坏
Flight systems damaged.
那就打开导航摄像头
Then activate guidance camera!
我来控制
Give me the wheel!
给希尔特工打电话
Get me Agent Hill.
通讯系统损坏
Communications array damaged.
还有好的地方吗
Well, what's not damaged?
空调系统完全正常
Air conditioning is fully operational.
前方交通堵塞
Traffic ahead.
那就给我换条路
Give me an alternate route.
罗斯福大桥上交通堵塞
Traffic alert on Roosevelt Bridge.
所有机动车禁行
All vehicles stopped.
17大街可行  正前方三个街区
17 Avenue clear in three blocks, directly ahead.
警告  接近十字路口
Warning, approaching intersection.
给我找条出路
Get me off the grid!
安全区域路线计算中
Calculating route to secure location.
真好  太好了
That's so sweet. That is so nice.
我得挂了  再见
Hey. I gotta go, though. Okay, bye.
我姑妈  她有点失眠
My aunt, she's kind of an insomniac.
好吧
Yep.
你要是  不介意的话
Hey, if you want... if you want,
可以用我的洗衣机
you're welcome to use my machine.
应该比地下室那个便宜
Might be cheaper than the one in the basement.
是吗  有多便宜
Oh, yeah? What's it cost?
一杯咖啡怎么样
A cup of coffee?
谢谢  但是
Thank you, but
我已经拿下去好多了  而且
I already have a load in downstairs, and, uh...
还是别用你的洗衣机洗我的白大褂了
you really don't want my scrubs in your machine.
我刚换班
I'm just finished rotation
从传染病房回来
in the infectious diseases ward, so.
那我还是保持距离吧
Ah, well, I'll keep my distance.
希望不要太远
Well hopefully not too far.
你的音响好像忘记关了
Oh, and I think you left your stereo on.
是吗  谢谢
Oh. Right, thank you.
我好像没给过你钥匙
I don't remember giving you a key.
你觉得我需要吗
You really think I'd need one?
我老婆把我赶出来了
My wife kicked me out.
我都不知道你结婚了
Didn't know you were married.
你不知道的事多了
There are a lot of things you don't about me.
这我倒知道  尼克  问题就在这
I know, Nick. That's the problem.
隔墙有耳
很抱歉我这样不请自来
I'm sorry to have do this,
但我真无处可去了
but I had no place else to crash.
神盾局暴露了
还有谁知道你老婆的事
Who else knows about your wife?
你和我
也就
Just...
我的朋友们吧
my friends.
我们算朋友吗
Is that what we are?
那取决于你了
That's up to you.
不要相信任何人
Don't trust anyone.
罗杰斯队长
Captain Rogers?
队长  我是神盾局特勤队13号特工
Captain, I'm Agent 13 of S.H.I.E.L.D's Special Service.
凯特
Kate?
我是来保护你的
I'm assigned to protect you.
谁派你来的
On whose order?
他
His.
狐步受伤  已经失去知觉
Foxtrot is down, he's unresponsive.
请派遣急救人员
I need EMTs.
确认枪手的位置了吗
Do you have a twenty on the shooter?
告诉他们我去追了
Tell them I'm in pursuit.
他能挺过来吗
Is he gonna make it?
不知道
I don't know.
杀手什么样
Tell me about the shooter.
动作快  有力量
He's fast and strong.
还有一条金属臂
He had a metal arm.
弹道分析
Ballistics?
三颗子弹
Three slugs.
没有膛线  完全无法辨识
No rifling and completely untraceable.
前苏联制造的
Soviet made?
是的
Yeah.
他不行了
He's dropping.
抢救车过来
Crash cart coming in.
护士  把单子拉开
Nurse, help me with the gauzes, please.
血压下降了  电击抢救
BP is dropping. Defibrillator!
充电至100焦耳
Charge to one hundred.
尼克  你不能死
Don't do this to me, Nick.
退后  三  二  一  开始
Stand back! Three, two, one. Clear!
有脉搏吗
Pulse?
没有
No pulse.
好  充电至200焦耳
Okay. Charge to two hundred, please.
退后  三  二  一  开始
Stand back! Three, two, one. Clear!
注射肾上腺素  有脉搏吗
Give me epinephrine! Pulse?
没有
Negative.
尼克  你不能这样  不能死
Don't do this to me, Nick. Don't do this to me.
现在几点
What's the time?
一点零三
03, Doctor.
死亡时间  凌晨一点零三分
Time of death, 1:03 A.M.
得把他带走
We need to take him.
娜塔莎
Natasha.
Natasha!
弗瑞怎么会去你家
Why was Fury in your apartment?
我也不知道
I don't know.
队长  他们叫你回神盾局
Captain, they want you back at S.H.I.E.L.D.
好的  稍等
Yeah, give me a second.
他们让你立刻回去
They want you now.
好的
Okay.
你真不会说谎
You're a terrible liar.
突击队立刻护送罗杰斯队长
S.T.R.I.K.E team escort Captain Rogers
返回神盾局
back to S.H.I.E.L.D immediately.
我跟他说了
I told him.
我们走
Let's go.
好
Yeah.
突击队  出发
S.T.R.I.K.E, move it out.
无论结果如何  你尽力了
For whatever it's worth, you did your best.
谢谢您  长官
Thank you, sir.
罗杰斯队长
Captain Rogers.
邻居
Neighbor.
队长  我是亚历山大·皮尔斯
Ah, Captain. I'm Alexander Pierce.
长官  很荣幸见到你
Sir, it's an honor.
感到荣幸的应该是我  队长
The honor is mine, Captain.
我父亲以前在101空降师  进来吧
My father served in the 101st. Come on in.
那张照片是我和尼克认识五年后拍的
That photo was taken five years after Nick and I met,
那时我在哥伦比亚国务院
when I was at State Department in Bogota.
哥伦比亚民族解放军占领使馆后
ELN rebels took the embassy,
警卫帮我逃了出来
and security got me out,
但是叛军抓走了人质
but the rebels took hostages.
尼克是神盾局在当地的负责人
Nick was deputy chief for the S.H.I.E.L.D station there.
他提出了一个计划
And he comes to me with a plan.
要通过下水道进行突袭
He wants to storm the building through the sewers.
我说  不行  我们会谈判的
I said, "No, we'll negotiate."
结果是  叛军不跟我们谈判
Turned out the ELN didn't negotiate,
于是下令格杀勿论
so they put out a kill order.
他们扫荡了地下室
They stormed the basement,
结果发现了什么呢  空的
and what did they find? They find it empty.
尼克没有听从我的直接命令
Nick had ignored my direct order
在外国境内  擅自下令
and carried out an unauthorized military operation
执行任务
on foreign soil.
营救了十几名政府官员
He saved the lives of a dozen political officers,
还有我的女儿
including my daughter.
所以你提拔了他
So you gave him a promotion.
我从不后悔这件事
I've never had any cause to regret it.
队长  尼克昨晚为什么在你家
Captain, why was Nick in your apartment last night?
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道那里被监听了吗
You know it was bugged?
知道  是尼克告诉我的
I did, because Nick told me.
那他告诉你是他监听的了吗
Did he tell you he was the one who bugged it?
我给你看样东西
I want you to see something.
巴托克  谁指使你的
Who hired you, Batroc?
这是直播吗
Is that live?
是的  他们昨晚在阿尔及尔的安全屋
Yeah, they picked him up last night
抓到了他  那地方也没多安全
in a not-so-safe house in Algiers.
你是说他是嫌犯
Are you saying he's a suspect?
巴托克可不喜欢暗杀
Assassination isn't Batroc's line.
不是他  比这要复杂得多
No, it's more complicated than that.
巴托克受一位匿名人士雇佣
Batroc was hired anonymously
袭击雷姆利亚星号
to attack the Lemurian Star
他们通过电子邮件联系
and he was contacted by e-mail
用电汇付款
and paid by wire transfer.
之后这笔钱经过了
And then the money was run through
十七个虚假账户转账
seventeen fictitious accounts,
最后转给一家控股公司
the last one going to a holding company
公司注册者叫雅各布·维奇
that was registered to a Jacob Veech.
我应该认识他吗
Am I supposed to know who that is?
不应该  维奇六年前就死了
Not likely. Veech died six years ago.
他最后的地址是
His last address was
埃尔姆赫斯特大街14-35号
14-35 Elmhurst Drive.
我第一次见尼克时
When I first met Nick
得知他母亲住在14-37号
his mother lived at 14-37.
你的意思是弗瑞雇了海盗吗
Are you saying Fury hired the pirates?
为什么呢
Why?
比较盛行的说法是
Well the prevailing theory
这种劫持不过是为了掩饰
was that the hijacking was a cover
机密情报的交易
for the acquisition and sale of classified intelligence.
交易出了岔  结果尼克送了命
The sale went sour and that led to Nick's death.
如果你真了解尼克·弗瑞
If you really knew Nick Fury
就该知道这不可能
you know that's not true.
不然你为什么会来见我
Why do you think we're talking?
你知道吗  我在理事会工作
See, I took a seat on the Council
不是我愿意  而是尼克请求的
not because I wanted to but because Nick asked me to,
因为我们都十分现实
because we were both realists.
我们知道  除去那些
We knew that despite all the diplomacy
外交手腕和虚情假意
and the handshaking and the rhetoric,
想建立更美好的新世界
that to build a really better world
有时需要摧毁旧的世界
sometimes means having to tear the old one down.
而这样难免树敌
And that makes enemies.
他们会说你无耻肮脏
Those people that call you dirty
因为你不惜做见不得人的事
because you got the guts to stick your hands in the mud
只为创造更美好的事物
and try to build something better.
一想到那些人现在过得悠然自在
And the idea that those people could be happy today,
就让我非常恼火
makes me really, really angry.
队长  你是尼克生前见到的最后一人
Captain, you were the last one to see Nick alive.
我认为这绝非巧合
I don't think that's an accident,
我想你也这样觉得
and I don't think you do either.
所以我再问你一次
So I'm gonna ask again,
他为什么会在你那
why was he there?
他告诉我不要相信任何人
He told me not to trust anyone.
也包括他吗
I wonder if that included him.
抱歉  那是他的遗言
I'm sorry. Those were his last words.
失陪
Excuse me.
队长
Captain.
有人杀害了我的朋友  我必须查明根源
Somebody murdered my friend and I'm gonna find out why.
挡我路的  我都会让他后悔
Anyone gets in my way, they're gonna regret it.
无论是谁
Anyone.
明白
Understood.
操作控制中心
Operations control.
已确认
Confirmed.
所有突击队员准备就位
All S.T.R.I.K.E personal on site.
明白
Understood.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
取证处
Forensics.
-已确认  -队长
- Confirmed. - Cap.
朗姆洛
Rumlow.
物证组在楼顶上发现了些纤维
Evidence response found some fibers
想让我们去看看
on the roof they want us to see.
要战术小队就位吗
You want me to get the tac-team ready?
先看看情况再说
No, lets wait and see what it is first.
好的
Right.
现在什么情况
What's the status so far?
行政层
Administrations level.
-确认  -借过
- Confirmed. - Excuse me.
借过
Excuse me.
弗瑞的事  我深表遗憾
Sorry about what happened with Fury.
真是惨剧
Messed up what happened to him.
谢谢
Thank you.
档案室
Records.
确认
Confirmed.
动手之前
Before we get started,
还有人想出去吗
does anyone want to get out?
紧急停止
派遣突击队至25楼
Mobilize S.T.R.I.K.E units, 25th floor.
悠着点  大个子
Woh, big guy.
这不是私人恩怨  队长
I just want you to know, Cap, this ain't personal.
我感觉就是私人恩怨
It kind of feels personal.
放下盾牌  举起双手
25th Floor Drop the shield! Put your hands in the air!
投降吧  罗杰斯
Give it up, Rogers!
把门打开
Get that door open!
你无路可逃了
You have nowhere to go!
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
他往车库去了  封闭大桥
He's headed for the garage. Lock down the bridge!
罗杰斯队长  立刻投降
Stand down, Captain Rogers. Stand down.
重复  立刻投降
Repeat, stand down.
都听好了
Eyes here.
无论手头上有什么事  都推掉
Whatever your op is, bury it.
现在是一级戒备
This is level one.
通知交通部  特区的路口全部亮红灯
Contact DOT. All traffic lights in the district go red.
封锁附近机场所有跑道
Shut all runways at BWI, IAD and Reagan.
将市区里的所有监控录像
All security cameras in the city
调到这个显示屏上
go through this monitor, right here.
追踪所有通讯设备
Scan all open sources.
电话  电脑  平板  能查的都查
Phones, computers, PDA's, whatever.
有人发微博我也要立刻知道
If someone Tweets about this guy, I want to know about it.
恕我直言
With all due respect,
如果神盾局要追捕美国队长
If S.H.I.E.L.D is conducting a manhunt for Captain America,
我们有权知道原因
we deserve to know why.
因为他骗了我们
Because he lied to us.
罗杰斯队长
Captain Rogers
知道弗瑞局长的死因
has information regarding the death of Director Fury,
却不愿告诉我们
he refused to share it.
我知道大家很难接受
As difficult as this is to accept,
但美国队长现在是神盾局的在逃犯
Captain America is a fugitive from S.H.I.E.L.D.
-哪去了  -安全的地方
- Where is it? - Safe.
说重点
Do better!
你哪里弄来的
Where did you get it?
凭什么告诉你
Why would I tell you?
弗瑞为什么要给你
Fury gave it to you. Why?
里面是什么
What's on it?
我不知道
I don't know.
别说谎
Stop lying!
我只是看上去什么都懂  罗杰斯
I only act like I know everything, Rogers.
你一定知道是弗瑞雇佣的海盗
I bet you knew Fury hired the pirates, didn't you?
一切就说得通了
Well, it makes sense.
那艘船有问题  你和弗瑞都要想办法上去
The ship was dirty, Fury needed a way in, so do you.
别让我再问你第二遍
I'm not gonna ask you again.
我知道谁杀了弗瑞
I know who killed Fury.
多数情报机构不相信他的存在
Most of the intelligence community doesn't believe he exists,
相信的称他为寒冬战士
the ones who do call him the Winter Soldier.
在过去的五十年里  他参与了二十多起
He's credited with over two dozen assassinations
暗杀事件
in the last fifty years.
所以说他像个鬼魂一样
So he's a ghost story.
五年前  我护送一个核武器工程师离开伊朗
Five years ago I was escorting a nuclear engineer out of Iran,
快到敖德萨时  有人射穿了我的轮胎
somebody shot at my tires near Odessa.
车失控掉下悬崖  我们逃了出来
We lost control, went straight over a cliff, I pulled us out,
寒冬战士也在那里
but the Winter Soldier was there.
见我挡着  他就一枪打穿了这里杀死了工程师
I was covering my engineer, so he shot him straight through me.
苏联子弹  没有膛线  穿不了比基尼了
A Soviet slag, no rifling. Bye-bye bikinis.
你现在穿比基尼一定很丑
Yeah, I bet you look terrible in them now.
追踪他是不现实的  我试过
Going after him is a dead end. I know, I've tried.
像你说的  他就是个鬼魂
Like you said, he's a ghost story.
那就看看那个鬼魂到底想要什么
Well, let's find out what the ghost wants.
尼克·弗瑞被残忍地谋杀了
Nick Fury was murdered in cold blood.
但凡是个正常人
To any reasonable person,
都会说他是烈士  而非叛徒
that would make him a martyr, not a traitor.
可他为什么是叛徒
You know what makes him a traitor?
他让雇佣兵劫持自己的船
Hiring a mercenary to hijack his own ship.
尼克·弗瑞利用与你的交情
Nick Fury used your friendship
强迫理事会延迟洞察计划
to coerce this council into delaying Project Insight.
他知道这个计划会暴露他的非法行动
A project he knew would expose his own illegal operations.
说好听点  他骗了你  说句不好听的
At best, he lied to you. At worst...
你们想让我引咎辞职吗
Are you calling for my resignation?
我现在就可以写辞呈
I've got a pen and paper right here.
这个我们可以迟点讨论
That discussion can be tabled for a later time.
你们还真想让我辞职
But you do want to have a discussion.
我们已经谈过了  部长先生
We've already had it, Mr. Secretary.
理事会决定立即重启洞察计划
This council moves to immediately reactivate Project Insight.
你要是想耍嘴皮子  赶紧趁现在
If you want to say something snappy, now would be a good time.
逃亡第一准则  只能走不能跑
First rule of going on the run is, don't run, walk.
如果穿着这双鞋跑  早就掉下来了
If I run in these shoes, they're gonna fall off.
这个驱动器拥有六级定位系统
The drive has a level six homing program,
一旦我们启动  神盾局就能定位我们
so as soon as we boot up S.H.I.E.L.D will know exactly where we are.
需要多长时间
How much time do we have?
九分钟吧  现在
About nine minutes from...
开始
Now.
弗瑞的猜测是对的
Fury was right about that ship,
有人想在那艘船上藏东西
somebody's trying to hide something.
雷姆利亚星号
这个驱动器被某种人工智能保护着
This drive is protected by some sort of AI,
一直在重组自己  抵抗我的指令
it keeps rewriting itself to counter my commands.
你能破解吗
Can you override it?
开发这个程序的人比我聪明点
The person who developed this is slightly smarter than me.
就那么一点
Slightly.
我要试试追踪程序
I'm gonna try running a tracer.
这是神盾局用来
This is a program that S.H.I.E.L.D
追踪恶意软件的程序
developed to track hostile malware,
就算我们读不到文件
so if we can't read the file,
也许可以查到它的来源
maybe we can find out where it came from.
有什么可以帮到你们的吗
Can I help you guys with anything?
没事
Oh, no.
我跟未婚夫正选地方度蜜月呢
My fiancé was just helping me with some honeymoon destinations.
是的  我们要结婚了
Right! We're getting married.
恭喜
Congratulations.
你们准备去哪呢
Where do you guys thinking about going?
新泽西州
New Jersey.
我也有这款眼镜
I have the exact same glasses.
你们还真像双胞胎
Wow, you two are practically twins.
我也希望有你的身材
Yeah, I wish. Specimen.
有什么需要的话可以找我
If you guys need anything,
-我叫本·亚伦  -谢谢
- I'm Ben Aaron. - Thank you.
说好的九分钟呢  快点
You said nine minutes, come on.
别紧张  好了
Shh, relax. Got it.
新泽西州维顿
你熟悉这地方吗
You know it?
以前很熟悉  走吧
I used to. Let's go.
标准战术小队
Standard tac-team.
两前两后  侧翼还有两个
Two behind, two across, two coming straight at us.
如果被发现了  我跟他们打
If they make us, I'll engage,
你搭南边的电梯去地铁站
you hit the south escalator to the metro.
闭嘴  搂着我  笑两声
Shut up and put your arm around me, laugh at something I said.
-什么  -快
- What? - Do it!
未发现信号源
Negative at the source.
搜索每一层楼
Give me a floor rundown.
三楼未发现目标
Negative on three.
二楼未发现目标
Negative on two.
从最高层往下搜  与我汇合
Scan the upper levels, work down to me.
吻我
Kiss me.
什么
What?
公共场合秀恩爱  让人很不自在
Public displays of affection make people very uncomfortable.
是的
Yes, they do.
还不自在吗
You still uncomfortable?
也不能这么说
It's not exactly the word I would use.
欢迎来到新泽西
{}花园之州
美国队长从哪学的偷车
Where did Captain America learn how to steal a car?
纳粹德国
Nazi Germany.
还有这车是借来的  脚别放在仪表盘上
And we're borrowing. Take your feet off the dash.
好吧  我有个问题
Alright, I have a question for you,
你可以不回答
of which you do not have to answer.
不过我觉得即使你不回答
I feel like if you don't answer it though,
也算是回答了
you're kind of answering it, you know?
什么问题
What?
这是你自1945年以后的第一次接吻吗
Was that your first kiss since 1945?
有那么糟吗
That bad, huh?
我可没这么说
I didn't say that.
听起来就是那个意思
Well, it kind of sounds like that's what you're saying.
不是  我只是好奇你练习过几次
No, I didn't. I just wondered how much practice you had.
-我不需要练习  -每个人都需要
- I don't need practice. - Everybody needs practice.
这不是我自1945年之后的第一次接吻
It was not my first kiss since 1945.
我是95岁了  可我不是死人
I'm ninety-five, I'm not dead.
没遇到过特别的人吗
Nobody special, though?
不管你信不信
Believe it or not,
要找个和我有类似人生经历的人不太容易
it's kind of hard to find someone with shared life experience.
管他的  你随便编个故事就好了
Well, that's alright, you just make something up.
像你一样吗
What, like you?
我不知道  说实话也要看情况
I don't know. The truth is a matter of circumstances,
不能对谁都掏心窝
it's not all things to all people all the time.
我也是
And neither am I.
这样活着很累
That's a tough way to live.
但能保命
It's a good way not to die, though.
不了解一个人的本质
You know, it's kind of hard to
你怎么信任他
trust someone when you don't know who that someone really is.
对
Yeah.
你希望我是什么样的人
Who do you want me to be?
朋友  你觉得怎么样
How about a friend?
我觉得你当初
Well, there's a chance you might
是入错行了  罗杰斯
be in the wrong business, Rogers.
是这吗
This is it?
文件就是从这发出的
The file came from these coordinates.
里海营
我也来自这里
So did I.
我在这个营地接受过训练
This camp is where I was trained.
变化很大吗
Changed much?
还好
A little.
节奏快点  姑娘们
Pick up the pace, ladies!
快  快  跑快点
Let's go! Let's go! Double time!
快  罗杰斯  快点
Come on Rogers, move it!
快点  集合了
Come on! Fall in!
罗杰斯  我说集合
Rogers! I said fall in!
这里没戏
This is a dead end.
没热成像  没信号  连无线电波都没有
Zero heat signature, zero waves, not even radio.
编写文件的人
Whoever wrote the file
应该用了路由器  防止别人追踪
must have used a router to throw people off.
怎么了
What is it?
军规有规定  营房五百码范围内
Army regulations forbid storing ammunition
禁止存放弹药
within five hundred yards from the barracks.
这栋建筑不该建在这
This building is in the wrong place.
这是神盾局的地方
This is S.H.I.E.L.D.
可能是在这成立的
Maybe where it started.
国
土
战
略
防
御
与
后
勤
保
局
障
那是斯塔克的爸爸
There's Stark's father.
霍华德
Howard.
这姑娘是谁
Who's the girl?
在这么隐秘的地方工作
If you already working in a secret office
为什么还要藏着电梯
why do you need to hide the elevator?
数据源不可能在这里  这些都是老古董了
This can't be the data-point, this technology is ancient.
是否启动系统
Initiate system?
输入  是
Y-E-S, spells yes.
我们玩个游戏吧
"Shall we play a game?"
-这是一部电影[1933《战争游戏》]的台词  -我看过
- It's from a movie that... - Yeah, I saw it.
史蒂夫·罗杰斯
Rogers, Steven.
1918年出生
Born, 1918.
娜塔莉·阿莲诺娃·罗曼诺夫
Romanoff, Natalia Alianovna.
1984年出生
Born, 1984.
这是录像吧
It's some kind of a recording.
我才不是录像  女士
I am not a recording, Fraulein.
或许我已经不是
I may not be the man I was
1945年队长抓到我时的样子
when the Captain took me prisoner in 1945,
但我是
but I am.
你认识这玩意吗
Do you know this thing?
阿尔宁·佐拉是红骷髅手下的德国科学家
Arnim Zola was a German scientist who worked for the Red Skull.
已经死了很多年了
He's been dead for years.
纠正第一点  我是瑞士人
First correction, I am Swiss.
第二点  看看周围
Second, look around you.
我还活得生龙活虎
I have never been more alive.
1972年  我被确诊为癌症晚期
In 1972 I received a terminal diagnosis.
科学拯救不了我的身体  但我的思想
Science could not save my body, my mind, however,
必须要留存
that was worth saving
于是存在了这两百万单元的数据库中
on two hundred thousand feet of data banks.
你们就在我的大脑里
You are standing in my brain.
你怎么会在这
How did you get here?
应邀而来
Invited.
二战之后的回形针行动
It was Operation Paperclip after World War II.
神盾局招募了具有战略价值的德国科学家
S.H.I.E.L.D recruited German scientists with strategic values.
他们觉得我能帮他们实现目标
They thought I could help their cause.
我也实现了自己的目标
I also helped my own.
九头蛇跟红骷髅一起消亡了
Hydra died with the Red Skull.
砍掉一个头  还会长出两个新的
Cut off one head, two more shall take its place.
证明给我看
Prove it.
存档读取中
Accessing archive.
九头蛇创立时的信条
Hydra was founded on the belief
是人类不能掌控自身的自由
that humanity could not be trusted with its own freedom.
可我们没意识到
What we did not realize,
若要夺走自由  他们会反抗
was that if you try to take that freedom, they resist.
领导我们统领
我们会追随九头蛇
战争教会了我们很多
The war taught us much.
人类需要自愿放弃自由
Humanity needed to surrender its freedom willingly.
战争结束之后  神盾局成立
After the war, S.H.I.E.L.D was founded
并招募了我
and I was recruited.
阿尔宁·佐拉博士
机密
新的九头蛇诞生了
The new Hydra grew.
德国科学家被美国征召
像神盾局里一条美丽的寄生虫
A beautiful parasite inside S.H.I.E.L.D.
七十年来
For seventy years
九头蛇一直在幕后煽动危机
Hydra has been secretly feeding crisis,
引发战争
reaping war.
当历史的发展与预期不符
And when history did not cooperate,
就改变历史
history was changed.
不明刺客
动机不明
不可能  神盾局不会放任你不管
That's impossible, S.H.I.E.L.D would have stopped you.
霍华和玛利亚·斯塔克在车祸中丧生
意外总是不可避免的
Accidents will happen.
死    亡
死 于 车 祸
死 亡
九头蛇制造了一个如此混乱的世界
Hydra created a world so chaotic
使得人类最终愿意
that humanity is finally ready
牺牲自由以换取安全
to sacrifice its freedom to gain its security.
一旦净化程序完成
Once the Purification Process is complete,
A172    号轨道
■
已获取位置
卫星上行链路
九头蛇的世界新秩序就会形成
Hydra's new world order will arise.
我们赢了  队长
We won, Captain.
你的死亡与你的人生一样
Your death amounts to the same as your life;
罗杰斯失踪
牺牲了
一切的
英雄
牺牲了
一切的
英雄
毫无意义
a zero sum.
刚才说到
As I was saying...
这U盘里是什么
What's on this drive?
洞察计划
Project Insight
需要洞察力  所以我编写了一个算法
requires insight. So I wrote an algorithm.
什么算法  有什么用
What kind of algorithm? What does it do?
你问题的答案足以让人心醉沉迷
The answer to your question is fascinating.
可惜  你们要死了  听不到了
Unfortunately, you shall be too dead to hear it.
史蒂夫  发现导弹
Steve, I got a bogey.
距离不远  最多只剩30秒
Short-range ballistic. Thirty seconds, tops.
导     袭
弹来
谁发射的
Who fired it?
神盾局
S.H.I.E.L.D.
我一直在拖延时间  队长
I am afraid I have been stalling, Captain.
认命吧  这样也是对你好
Admit it, it's better this way.
我们都一样  没时间了
We're both of us out of time.
召回全员吧
Call in the asset.
我要走了  皮尔斯先生
I'm going to go, Mr. Pierce.
走之前你还需要我做什么吗
You need anything before I leave?
没了  没事  勒娜特  你回家吧
No. It's fine, Renata, you can go home.
好的  晚安
Okay, night-night.
晚安
Good night.
要喝牛奶吗
Want some milk?
时间安排有变
The timetable has moved.
机会十分难得
Our window is limited.
两个六级目标
Two targets, Level six.
他们已经害我失去了佐拉
They already cost me Zola.
十小时之内都要杀死
I want confirmed death in ten hours.
抱歉  皮尔斯先生  我
Sorry, Mr. Pierce,  I...
忘记拿手机了
I forgot my phone.
勒娜特  你真该敲门的
Oh, Renata. I wish you would have knocked.
早啊
Hey, man.
真抱歉  我们需要避避风头
I'm sorry about this. We need a place to lay low.
认识的人都想杀了我们
Everyone we know is trying to kill us.
除了我
Not everyone.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
怎么了
What's going on?
我当初加入神盾局的时候
When I first joined S.H.I.E.L.D,
还以为有多光明正大
I thought it was going straight.
其实也就是从克格勃换到了九头蛇
But I guess I just traded in the KGB for Hydra.
我本以为知道我在为谁撒谎  但...
I thought I knew whose lies I was telling, but...
现在我也分不清了
I guess I can't tell the difference anymore.
人生总有走错路的时候
There's a chance you might be in the wrong business.
我欠你个人情
I owe you.
没什么
It's okay.
换成是我
If it was the other way around,
你的命攥在我手里
and it was down to me to save your life,
说实话
and you be honest with me,
你会把性命托付给我吗
would you trust me to do it?
现在会了
I would now.
我从不说谎
And I'm always honest.
刚发现自己白牺牲了一次
Well, you seem pretty chipper for someone
你还能这么乐观
who just found out they died for nothing.
我知道对手是谁就很开心了
Well, I guess I just like to know who I'm fighting.
我做了早饭
I made breakfast.
你们吃人间烟火吧
If you guys eat that sort of thing.
问题是
So, the question is:
神盾局里有谁有能力在境内发射导弹
who in S.H.I.E.L.D could launch a domestic missile strike?
皮尔斯
Pierce.
他碰巧正坐在
Who happens to be sitting
全世界最安全的大楼顶层
on top of the most secure building in the world.
但他不是孤军奋战
But he's not working alone,
佐拉的算法在雷姆利亚星号上
Zola's algorithm was on the Lemurian Star.
贾斯珀·西特韦尔也在上面
So was Jasper Sitwell.
所以最关键的问题是
So, the real question is:
两个华盛顿的头号通缉犯
how do the two most wanted people in Washington
怎么在光天化日下绑架神盾局官员
kidnap a S.H.I.E.L.D officer in broad daylight?
答案是  不需要绑架
The answer is: you don't.
这是什么
What's this?
算是简历吧
Call it a resume.
这是巴马拉吗
Is this Bakhmala?
你参加了哈立德·汗迪尔任务
The Khalid Khandil mission, that was you.
你可没说他是空降救援
You didn't say he was a para-rescue.
这位是莱利吗
Is this Riley?
没错
Yeah.
我听说因为有火箭弹  直升机飞不进去
I heard they couldn't bring in the choppers because of the RPGs.
你们用的是什么  隐形降落伞吗
What did you use, a stealth chute?
不  是这个
No. These.
你不是说自己是飞行员吗
I thought you said you're a pilot.
我可没说过
I never said a pilot.
我不能请你帮忙  山姆
I can't ask you to do this, Sam.
你退役是有原因的
You got out for a good reason.
伙计  美国队长要我帮忙
Dude, Captain America needs my help.
这理由还不够吗
There's no better reason to get back in.
这东西哪能拿到
Where can we get our hands on one of these things?
最后一套在米德堡
The last one is at Fort Meade,
三道防护门和一堵十二英寸厚的钢墙后面
behind three guarded gates and a twelve-inch steel wall.
应该没什么问题
Shouldn't be a problem.
EXO-7  猎鹰
机密
我今晚得飞回家
Listen, I gotta fly home tonight,
选区出了点问题
cause I got some constituency problem,
我得处理一下
and I gotta press the flesh.
是哪位选民有问题吗  议员先生
Any constituent in particular, Mr. Senator?
不算是吧
Uh...no, not really.
二十三岁  有点火辣  相当辣
Twenty-three, kind of hot. Real hot.
我记得她想当个记者
You know, wants to be a reporter, I think.
不记得了  谁有心思听她说话
I don't know, who listens at that point?
好像不是大问题啊
Doesn't sound much of a problem to me.
是吗  她把我的后背抓的疼死了
Really? Cause she's killing my back.
这地方不适合谈这些
Look, this isn't the place to talk about it.
别针不错
That's a nice pin.
多谢夸奖
Thank you.
抱一个
Come here.
九头蛇万岁
Hail, Hydra.
你看到了吧
See that, right?
是啊  看到了
I just saw that, yeah.
-我该去检查检查吗  -检查一下吧
- Should I get it checked? - I think so.
亚历山大·皮尔斯
你们先去把车开过来
I need a minute. Bring the car around.
你好  长官
Yes, sir.
西特韦尔特工  午餐吃得好吗
Agent Sitwell, how was lunch?
听说这里的蟹饼相当不错
I hear the crab cakes here are delicious.
你是谁
Who is this?
十点钟方向戴着墨镜的帅哥
The good looking guy in the sunglasses, your ten o'clock.
另一个十点钟方向
Your other ten o'clock.
看到了吧
There you go.
你想干什么
What do you want?
你在拐角那右拐
You're gonna go around the corner, to your right.
第二个车位上有辆灰色车
There's a grey car, two spaces down.
我们去兜个风
You and I are gonna take a ride.
我为什么要听你的
And why would I do that?
因为那条领带看起来挺贵的
Because that tie looks really expensive,
我不想弄脏了
and I'd hate to mess it up.
告诉我佐拉算法的事
Tell me about Zola's algorithm.
从没听说过
Never heard of it.
你在雷姆利亚星号上干了什么
What were you doing on the Lemurian Star?
晕船了  一直在吐
I was throwing up, I get seasick.
搞这出是想暗示我
Is this little display meant to insinuate
你能把我从屋顶扔下去吗
that you can throw me off the roof?
这可不是你的作风  罗杰斯
Cause it's really not your style, Rogers.
说对了  的确不是
You're right. It's not.
是她的作风
It's hers.
等一下  会计部的那姑娘怎么样
Oh, wait. What about that girl from accounting,
叫劳拉
Laura... Laura...?
是莉莉安  有唇环的那个吧
Lillian. Lip piercing, right?
没错  她挺可爱的
Yeah, she's cute.
我还是没法接受唇环
Yeah, I'm not ready for that.
佐拉的算法是个程序
Zola's algorithm is a program...
为洞察计划选择目标
for choosing Insight's targets!
什么目标
What targets?
你
You!
开罗的电视主持人
A TV anchor in Cairo,
国防部副部长
the Undersecretary of Defense,
艾奥瓦城的高中毕业致辞学生
a high school valedictorian in Iowa city.
布鲁斯·班纳  斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇[奇异博士]
Bruce Banner, Stephen Strange,
任何威胁到九头蛇的人
anyone who's a threat to Hydra!
不论现在还是未来
Now, or in the future.
未来  它怎么预测未来
The Future? How could it know?
当然可以
How could it not?
21世纪就是一本电子书
The 21st century is a digital book.
佐拉教会了九头蛇读懂它
Zola taught Hydra how to read it.
你们的银行记录  病史
Your bank records, medical histories,
投票倾向  电子邮件  打的电话
voting patterns, e-mails, phone calls,
还有该死的SAT成绩
your damn SAT scores.
佐拉的算法通过分析人们的过去
Zola's algorithm evaluates peoples' past
预测他们的未来
to predict their future.
然后呢
And what then?
老天  皮尔斯会杀了我的
Oh, my God. Pierce is gonna kill me.
然后呢
What then?!
然后洞察计划的直升航母会除掉他们
Then the Insight Helicarriers scratch people off the list.
一次解决几百万人
A few millions at a time.
九头蛇可不喜欢泄密者
Hydra doesn't like leaks.
那你自己把嘴塞上
So why don't you try sticking a cork in it.
洞察计划16小时候启动
Insight's launching in sixteen hours,
我们时间有点紧
we're cutting it a little bit close here.
我知道  我们用他绕过DNA扫描
I know. We'll use him to bypass the DNA scans
直接上直升航母
and access the Helicarriers directly.
什么  你们疯了吗
What?! Are you crazy?
这主意糟透了
That is a terrible, terrible idea.
我靠
Shit!
抓紧
Hang on!
她交给我
I have her.
你们去找他
Find him.
快走  这里交给我
Go, I got this!
着陆地点  弗吉尼亚路2300街区
I make an LZ, twenty-three hundred block at Virginia Avenue.
两分钟后会合
Rendezvous two minutes.
有平民受到威胁
Civilians threatened.
重复  有平民受到威胁
Repeat, civilians threatened.
着陆地点  弗吉尼亚路2300街区
I make an LZ, twenty-three hundred block at Virginia Avenue.
回 放
两分钟后会合
Rendezvous two minutes.
让开  快让开
Get out of the way! Stay out of the way!
巴基
Bucky?
谁他妈是巴基
Who the hell is Bucky?
放下盾牌  队长  跪在地上
Drop the shield, Captain! On your knees!
跪在地上  快跪下  跪下
Get on your knees! Now! Get down! Get down!
跪在地上  跪下
Get on your knees! Down!
不许动
Don't move.
把枪放下  在这别这样
Put the gun down. Not here. Not here!
是他
It was him.
他就这么看着我  却不认识我
He looked right at me and he didn't even know me.
怎么可能
How's that even possible?
都七十年过去了
It was like seventy years ago.
是佐拉干的
Zola.
巴基所在的部队在1943年被俘
Bucky's whole unit was captured in '43,
佐拉拿他们做人体实验
Zola experimented on 'em.
可能就是因为这样  他摔下火车后活了下来
Whatever he did, it helped Bucky survive the fall.
他们一定找到了他
They must have found him.
这不是你的错  史蒂夫
None of that's your fault, Steve.
即使我一无所有的时候  我还有巴基
Even when I had nothing, I had Bucky.
快找个医生过来
We need to get a doctor here.
如果不压紧伤口
We don't put pressure on that wound
她会失血过多死在车上的
she's gonna bleed out here in the truck.
这玩意压得我头疼
That thing was squeezing my brain.
这人是谁
Who's this guy?
三个坑  开挖吧
Three holes. Start digging.
她中枪了  失血一品脱
GSW. She's lost at least a pint.
也许有两品脱
Maybe two.
交给我吧
Let me take her!
她会想先见见他的
She'll wants to see him first.
终于来了
About damn time.
脊柱损伤  胸骨断裂
Lacerated spinal column, cracked sternum,
锁骨粉碎  肝穿孔
shattered collarbone, perforated liver,
再加上要命的头疼
one hell of a headache.
别忘了肺萎陷
Don't forget your collapsed lung.
对  这可不能忘了  除此之外都挺好
Oh, let's not forget that. Otherwise, I'm good.
可他们给你做了开膛手术  你心跳都停了
They cut you open, your heart stopped.
河豚毒素B  能把脉搏降到一分钟一下
Tetrodotoxin B. Slows the pulse to one beat a minute.
班纳发明用来控制压力的
Banner developed it for stress.
对他没多大作用  但我们发现了它的新用途
Didn't work so great for him, but we found a use for it.
为什么要这么保密  为什么不告诉我们
Why all the secrecy? Why not just tell us?
为了让意图谋害局长的人以为暗杀成功了
Any attempt on the director's life had to look successful.
死人不能再死一次
Can't kill you if you're already dead.
另外  我也不知道还能相信谁
Besides, I wasn't sure who to trust.
银  行
巴恩斯中士
Sergeant Barnes...
巴基  不
Bucky, no!
改造程序已经开始了
The procedure has already started.
你将会成为九头蛇的新武器
You are to be the new face of Hydra.
把他冷冻起来
Put him on ice.
长官  他  他状态不稳定  情绪失常
Sir, he's...he's unstable. Erratic.
任务汇报
Mission report.
开始任务汇报
Mission report, now.
桥上的那个人
The man on the bridge...
他是谁
Who was he?
这星期早些时候你执行另一个任务时见过他
You met him earlier this week on another assignment.
我认识他
I knew him.
你做的事造福了全人类
Your work has been a gift to mankind.
你塑造了这个世纪
You shaped this century,
我需要你再做一次
and I need you to do it one more time.
人类社会正处在秩序与混乱的临界点
Society is at a tipping point between order and chaos.
明天早上我们要帮他们抉择
Tomorrow morning we're gonna give it a push.
但如果你不完成你的任务  我就没法着手
But if you don't do your part, I can't do mine,
九头蛇就没法还世界它应得的自由
and Hydra can't give the world the freedom it deserves.
可我认识他
But I knew him.
给他准备
Prep him.
他脱离低温冷冻太久了
He's been out of cryo-freeze too long.
那就给他洗脑  重新来过
Then wipe him and start over.
这个人拒绝接受诺贝尔和平奖
This man declined the Nobel Peace Prize.
亚历山大·皮尔斯
参谋长联席会议
他说  和平不是一项成就
He said, "Peace wasn't an achievement,
而是一种责任
it was a responsibility."
就是这种事害得我有了信任危机
See, it's stuff like this that gives me trust issues.
我们得阻止航母发射
We have to stop the launch.
我觉得理事会不会再接我的电话了
I don't think the Council's accepting my calls anymore.
这是什么
What's that?
直升航母飞到三千英尺高后
Once the Helicarriers reach three thousand feet,
会利用洞察卫星三角定位
they'll triangulate with Insight Satellites
洞 察 计 划
变成杀伤性武器
becoming fully weaponized.
洞 察 计 划
我们必须渗入航母
We need to breach those carriers
洞 察 计 划
将上面的定位模块换成我们自己的
and replace their targeting blades with our own.
洞 察 计 划
只换一两个没用
One or two won't cut it.
必须把三艘航母都连接到一起
We need to link all three carriers for this to work,
因为即使只剩一艘航母正常运转
because if even one of those ships remains operational
还是会死很多人
a whole lot of people are gonna die.
我们必须假设航母上的都是九头蛇的人
We have to assume everyone aboard those carriers is Hydra.
我们得闯过他们那一关
We need to get pass them,
把模块插进服务器  也许
insert the server blades, and maybe,
只是也许  我们可以挽救
just maybe, we can salvage what's left...
我们什么都不挽救
We're not salvaging anything.
我们不止要摧毁航母
We're not just taking down the carriers,
尼克  我们还要打倒神盾局
Nick, we're taking down S.H.I.E.L.D.
神盾局跟此事无关
S.H.I.E.L.D had nothing to do with it.
你把任务交给我  结果就是这样
You gave me this mission, this is how it ends.
神盾局被九头蛇渗透了
S.H.I.E.L.D's been compromised,
这是你自己说的
you've said so yourself.
九头蛇在就在你眼皮底下  却没有人发现
Hydra was right under your nose and nobody noticed.
我们为什么要在这个山洞里见面
Why do you think we're meeting in this cave?
因为我发现了
I noticed.
在你发现之前有多少人付出了生命的代价
And how many paid the price before you did?
我真的不知道巴恩斯的事
Look, I didn't know about Barnes.
就算你知道  你会告诉我吗
Even if you have, would you have told me?
还是继续你所谓的各司其职
Or would you have compartmentalized that too?
神盾局  九头蛇  一个都不能留
S.H.I.E.L.D, Hydra, it all goes.
他说得对
He's right.
别看我
Don't look at me.
他做什么我就做什么  就是比他慢点
I do what he does, just slower.
好吧
Well...
看来现在该由你来下令了  队长
Looks like you're giving the orders now, Captain.
我们找过你
We looked for you after.
我父母想开车从墓地送你回家
My folks wanted to give you a ride from the cemetery.
我知道  很抱歉
I know, I'm sorry.
我只是  想一个人待一会儿
I just kind of wanted to be alone.
葬礼怎么样
How was it?
就那样吧  我妈葬在了我爸身旁
It was okay. She's next to Dad.
我想问你...
I was gonna ask...
我知道你想问什么  巴基  只是我
I know what you're gonna say, Buck, I just...
我们可以像小时候那样  把沙发垫铺在地板上
We can put the couch cushion on the floor like when we were kids.
多好玩啊  你只要帮我擦擦鞋
It'll be fun. All you gotta do is shine my shoes,
或者倒个垃圾什么的就行了
maybe take out the trash.
来吧
Come on.
谢谢  巴基  不过我自己能行
Thank you, Buck, but I can get by on my own.
问题是  你不必这样
The thing is, you don't have to.
我会陪你走到最后的  哥们
I'm with you till the end of the line, pal.
他一定会在那儿
He's gonna be there, you know?
我知道
I know.
听着  不管他以前怎么样  现在的他
Look, whoever he used to be, the guy he is now,
不值得你去拯救了
I don't think he's the kind you save.
你需要阻止他
He's the kind you stop.
我不知道我下不下得去手
I don't know if I could do that.
他也许会逼得你没得选
Well, he might not give you a choice.
他不记得你了
He doesn't know you.
他会的
He will.
时间到了  准备出发
Gear up, it's time.
你就穿这身去吗
You gonna wear that?
不  要去打仗
No. If you're gonna fight a war,
就得穿上军装
you gotta wear a uniform.
完了  饭碗丢了
Oh, man. I am so fired!
进入发射的最后阶段
We are in final launch sequence.
洞察 发射
制导系统就绪
We are go on guidance.
所有人员请前往发射台
All personnel, to launch station.
飞行旅途如何
And how was your flight?
很不错  不过从机场来这的路上不怎么样
Lovely. The ride from the airport less so.
很遗憾神盾局没法控制一切
Sadly, S.H.I.E.L.D can't control everything.
包括美国队长
Including Captain America.
这里的身份认证靠生物识别
This facility is biometrically controlled,
这胸章能让你们在这里畅通无阻
and these will give you unrestricted access.
我把车停在这两个月了
I've been parking there for two months.
可这是他的车位
But it's his spot.
那他去哪了
So where's he been?
大概去阿富汗了吧
I think Afghanistan.
不可以  DT-6  着陆航线已满
Negative, DT-6. The pattern is full.
他可以事先说明的
Well, he could have said something.
天线出问题了吧
Must be the dish.
我去看看
I'll check it out.
麻烦让一下
Excuse us.
我知道过程很坎坷
I know the road hasn't exactly been smooth,
你们中可能有人
and some of you would
早就看我不顺眼了
have gladly kicked me out of the car along the way.
我们终于齐聚在这  全世界都将心存感激
Finally we're here, and the world should be grateful.
所有神盾局特工注意
Attention, all S.H.I.E.L.D agents.
我是史蒂夫·罗杰斯
This is Steve Rogers.
这几天你们听到了不少我的消息
You've heard a lot about me over the last few days,
有些人甚至奉命追捕我
some of you were even ordered to hunt me down.
但我认为应该告诉你们真相
But I think it's time you know the truth.
神盾局并不是我们想象的样子
S.H.I.E.L.D is not what we thought it was,
它已经被九头蛇渗透了
it's been taken over by Hydra.
他们的首领是亚历山大·皮尔斯
Alexander Pierce is their leader.
突击队和洞察计划也被渗透了
The S.T.R.I.K.E and Insight crew are Hydra as well.
我不知道还有多少  但他们在这里
I don't know how many more, but I know they're in the building.
可能就站在你身边
They could be standing right next to you.
他们差点如愿以偿  得到绝对控制权
They almost have what they want: absolute control.
尼克·弗瑞的被害只是个开始
They shot the Nick Fury and it won't end there.
如果你们今天发射了直升航母
If you launch those helicarriers today,
九头蛇将能够杀死
Hydra will be able to kill anyone
任何妨碍他们计划的人
that stands in their way,
除非我们阻止他们
unless we stop them.
我知道这很难做到
I know I'm asking a lot,
但自由的代价一向是高昂的
but the price of freedom is high, it always has been,
我愿意付出这代价
and it's a price I'm willing to pay.
哪怕只有我一个人  我也会坚持到底
And if I'm the only one, then so be it.
但我相信我不是一个人
But I'm willing to bet I'm not.
你是背的稿子
Did you write that down first,
还是临场发挥的
or was it off the top of your head?
你这婊子养的
You smug son of a bitch.
把他抓起来
Arrest him.
看来还是我说了算
I guess I've got the floor.
提前发射进程
Preempt the launch sequence,
现在就把航母送上天
send those ships up now.
你有意见吗
Is there a problem?
我
I'm...
你有意见吗
Is there a problem?
抱歉  长官
I'm sorry, sir.
我不会发射航母的
I'm not gonna launch those ships.
队长有令
Captain's orders.
离开你的操作台
Move away from your station.
他说了
Like he said.
队长有令
Captain's orders.
你站错边了  特工
You picked the wrong side, agent.
先看看自己的处境吧
Depends on where you're standing.
关闭舰湾闸门
Close the bay door!
快关上闸门  快关上
Close the bay door now! Close the bay door!
他们启动发射了
They're initiating launch.
队长
Hey, Cap,
怎么区分坏人和好人
how do we know the good guys from the bad guys?
朝你开枪的就是坏人
If they're shooting at you, they're bad.
队长
Hey, Cap,
我碰到你说的坏人了
I found those bad guys you were talking about.
你还好吗
You okay?
还没死
Not dead yet.
容我问一个问题
Let me ask you a question.
如果巴基斯坦明天攻进了孟买
What if Pakistan marched into Mumbai tomorrow,
而你清楚地知道
and you knew that they were gonna
他们会把你们的女儿拖到足球场里处决
drag your daughters into a soccer stadium for execution?
而你按一下按钮
And you could just stop
就能阻止这一切  你会按吗  你们呢
it with a flick of a switch. Would you? Wouldn't you all?
我不用你的按钮
Not if it was your switch.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
打断你的演讲了吗
Did I step on your moment?
卫星到达三千英尺高度
Satellites in range at three thousand feet.
猎鹰  情况如何
Falcon, status?
交战中
Engaging.
队长  我进来了
Alright, Cap, I'm in.
我靠
Shit!
还有八分钟  队长
Eight minutes, Cap.
我在努力了
Working on it.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
她在解除安全协议
She's disabling security protocols
把所有秘密公布到网上
and dumping all the secrets onto the Internet.
包括九头蛇的
Including Hydra's.
也有神盾局的  一旦你这么做
And S.H.I.E.L.D's. If you do this,
你们的过去就都大白于天下了
none of your past is gonna remain hidden.
你确定想让
Are you sure you're ready
全世界都看到你的真面目吗
for the world to see you as you really are?
那你呢
Are you?
A船替换完成
Alpha locked.
猎鹰  你在哪里
Falcon, where are you now?
我得先兜个圈子
I had to take a detour!
我进来了
I'm in.
B船替换完成
Bravo locked.
解决两个  还剩一个
Two down, one to go.
全体神盾局飞行员  紧急起飞
All S.H.I.E.L.D pilots, scramble.
我们是罗杰斯队长仅有的空中支援
We're the only air support Captain Rogers has got.
访问 受限
解锁是行政命令
Disabling the encryption is an executive order,
需要两名A级人员
it takes two Alpha Level members.
别担心  人马上就到
Don't worry, company's coming.
你收到我的花了吗
Did you get my flowers?
我很高兴你能来  尼克
I'm glad you're here, Nick.
是吗
Really?
因为我以为是你杀了我
Cause I thought you had me killed.
你知道游戏规则的
You know how the game works.
为什么让我做神盾局局长
So why make me head of S.H.I.E.L.D?
因为你是我认识的
Cause you're the best
最好的  最无情的人
and the most ruthless person I ever met.
我在尽力保护人民
I did what I did to protect people.
我的敌人就是你的敌人  尼克
Our enemies are your enemies, Nick.
混乱  战争  脏弹袭击莫斯科
Disorder, war. It's just a matter of time
或者EMP轰炸芝加哥只是迟早的事
before a dirty bomb goes off in Moscow, or an EMP fries Chicago.
靠外交吗  治标不治本
Diplomacy? Holding action, a band-aid.
你知道我是在哪里想清楚的  波哥大[哥伦比亚]
And you know where I learned that: Bogota.
你没有问  只是做了该做的事
You didn't ask, you just did what had to be done.
牺牲两百万性命
I can bring order to the lives of seven billion people
就能拯救七十亿人
by sacrificing twenty million.
如果你敢迈出去  这就是下一步  尼克
It's the next step, Nick, if you have the courage to take it.
我有胆量不迈出去
No, I have the courage not to.
虹膜扫描开启
Retinal scanner active.
你以为我们不会取消你的权限吗
You don't you think we wiped your clearance from the system?
我知道你删了我的密码  应该还有扫描记录
I know you erased my password, probably deleted my retinal scan,
但如果你想先我一步  部长先生
but if you want to stay ahead of me, Mr. Secretary...
就得时刻瞪大双眼
You need to keep both eyes open.
A级人员确认
Alpha Level confirmed.
加密解锁  保密协议取消
Encryption code accepted. Safeguards removed.
C号航母在左前方45度
Charlie Carrier's forty-five degrees off the port bow.
六分钟
Six minutes.
山姆  我需要搭个便车
Hey, Sam, I'm gonna need a ride.
收到  准备好了通知我
Roger! Let me know when you're ready.
已经准备好了
I just did!
你比看起来重多了
You know, you're a lot heavier than you look.
我早饭吃多了
I had a big breakfast.
史蒂夫
Steve!
队长  队长  你还好吗
Cap? Cap, come in. Are you okay?
收到  我还在直升航母上
Yeah, I'm here! I'm still on the Helicarrier.
你在哪里
Where are you?
我着陆了  战衣坏了  抱歉
I'm grounded, the suit's down. Sorry, Cap.
别担心  我能行
Don't worry, I got it.
长官  理事会被控制了
Sir, Council's been breached.
说详细情况
Repeat dispatch.
黑寡妇在上面
Black Widow's up there.
我现在上去
Headed up!
猎鹰
Falcon?
什么事
Yeah?
朗姆洛往议会方向去了
Rumlow's headed for the Council.
我来
I'm on it.
会有很多人丧命的  巴基
People are gonna die, Buck.
我不能坐视不理
I can't let that happen.
求你别逼我这么做
Please, don't make me do this.
传输 完成
好了
Done.
这么快就走红了
And it's trending.
不想被烧出个两英寸的洞
Unless you want two inch hole in your sternum,
就放下枪
I'd put that gun down.
你一戴上  它就启动了
That was armed the moment you pinned it on.
放下枪
Drop it!
松手
我在41楼
I'm on forty-one,
正在朝西南楼梯井走
headed towards the south-west stairwell.
你要吃苦头了
This is gonna hurt.
九头蛇里没有罪犯
There are no prisoners with Hydra,
只有秩序
just order.
而只有经历痛苦  才有秩序
And order only comes through pain.
准备好受苦了吗
You ready for yours?
快闭嘴吧你
Man, shut the hell up.
中尉  还要多久
Lieutenant, how much longer?
65秒后接通卫星线路
Sixty-five seconds to satellite link.
重新确定目标  下弦武器准备
Target reengaged. Lowering weapons array now.
一分钟
One minute.
30秒  队长
Thirty seconds, Cap!
马上
Stand by.
高度已到达三千英尺
We've reached three thousand feet.
卫星系统上线
Satellite coming online now.
开始计算
Deploy algorithm.
获取 目标
计算已开始
Algorithm deployed.
可以获取目标了
We are go to targets.
已获取目标
马修·埃利斯总统  华盛顿
目标数量饱和  已分配完毕
Targets saturation reached. All targets assigned.
随时可以开火
Fire when ready.
准备开火  三  二  一
Firing in, three, two, one.
C船替换完成
Charlie locked.
目标呢  目标都去哪儿了
Where are the targets? Where are the targets?
好了队长  离开那里
Okay, Cap, get out of there.
重新定向
已获取目标
现在开火
Fire now.
但是  史蒂夫
But, Steve...
开火  现在就开火
Do it! Do it now!
真是浪费
What a waste.
你还怀疑罗杰斯会失败吗
Are you still on the fence about Roger's chances?
该走了  女理事
Time to go, Councilwoman.
这边走  快点  你要带我飞离这里
This way, come on. You're gonna fly me out of here.
知道吗  曾经我愿意为你挡子弹
You know, there was a time I would have taken a bullet for you.
你已经挡过了  必要时你还会
You already did. You will again when...
重  启
已启动
罗曼诺夫
Romanoff!
娜塔莎
Natasha!
娜塔莎  醒醒
Natasha, come on!
那玩意儿还真疼
Ow. Those really do sting.
九头蛇万岁
Hail, Hydra.
你完全不是对手  小鬼
You're out of your depth, kid.
拜托告诉我你在那架直升机上
Please, tell me you got that chopper in the air!
山姆  你在哪
Sam, where are you?
41楼  西北角
41st floor, north-west corner!
我们就来  待着别动
We're on it, stay where you are.
不可能
Not an option!
41楼  41楼
41st floor! 41st!
他们又没把楼层号
It's not like they put the floor numbers
标在大楼的外墙上
on the outside of the building!
希尔  史蒂夫呢  知道罗杰斯在哪吗
Hill, where's Steve? You got a location on Rogers?
你认识我
You know me.
我不认识
No, I don't!
巴基  你从小就认识我
Bucky, you've known me your whole life.
你的名字是詹姆斯·布坎南·巴恩斯
Your name is James Buchanan Barnes.
闭嘴
Shut up!
我是不会跟你打的
I'm not gonna fight you.
你是我的朋友
You're my friend.
你是我的任务
You're my mission.
那就完成任务
Then finish it.
因为我会陪你走到最后的
Cause I'm with you till the end of the line.
在你左边
On your left.
斯塔克工业
为什么现在还没有罗杰斯队长的消息
Why haven't we yet heard from Captain Rogers?
我不知道他还有什么可说的
I don't know what's left for him to say.
我认为波托马克河
I think the rock in the middle
中央的残骸已经表明了一切
of the Potomac made his point fairly eloquently.
他可以解释一下  这个国家该怎么
Well, he could explain how this country's expected to
维护自己的安全
maintain its national security now that
因为你们俩毁掉了我们的情报机构
he and you have laid waste our intelligence apparatus.
九头蛇卖给你们的是谎言  不是情报
Hydra was selling you lies, not intelligence.
好像大部分都是你亲自告诉我们的
Many of which you seem to have had a personal hand in telling.
特工  你应该知道
Agent, you should know that
委员会中有些成员
there are some on this committee who feel,
考虑到你既服务过这个国家
given your service record,
也背叛过这个国家
both for this country and against it,
你应该被处以监禁  而不是在国会山和我们顶嘴
that you belong in a penitentiary, not mouthing off on Capitol Hill.
你们不会把我关进监狱的
You're not gonna put me in a prison.
你们不会把任何人关进去的  知道为什么吗
You're not gonna put any of us in a prison. You know why?
请指点吧
Do enlighten us.
因为你们需要我们
Because you need us.
是的  这个世界很脆弱
Yes, the world is a vulnerable place,
是的  我们对此负有责任
and yes, we helped make it that way.
但我们也是最能保护它的人
But we're also the ones best qualified to defend it.
所以你们要想逮捕我  就动手吧
So if you want to arrest me, arrest me.
你们知道去哪里找我
You'll know where to find me.
你之前经历过这种事情
So, you've experienced this sort of things before?
你会习惯的
You get used to it.
尼古拉斯·弗瑞上校
正义的一生
我们在挖掘九头蛇的资料
We've been data-mining Hydra's files.
好像有很多漏网之鱼
Looks Like a lot of rats didn't go down with the ship.
我今晚启程去欧洲  你要一起吗
I'm heading to Europe tonight, wanted to ask if you'd come.
我还有事要做
There's something I gotta do first.
你呢  威尔森  我需要你这样的人
How about you, Wilson? I could use a man with your abilities.
比起间谍  我更喜欢当士兵
I'm more of a soldier than a spy.
好吧
Alright then.
要是有人问起我  让他们来这里找我
Anybody asks for me, tell them they can find me right here.
你该感到荣幸
You should be honored,
这是他说的最客气的话了
that's about as close as he gets to saying thank you.
你不跟他一起吗
Not going with him?
不
No.
也不留下
Not staying here?
我的身份全都暴露了  我得去弄个新的
I blew all my covers, I gotta go figure out a new one.
那得花上一段时间
That might take a while.
正好歇一阵子
I'm counting on it.
你要的那个东西
That thing you asked for,
我找基辅的几个朋友帮了些忙
I called in a few favors from Kiev.
第17号案件
算是帮我个忙  约那个护士吧
Will you do me a favor? Call that nurse.
她可不是护士
She's not a nurse.
你也不是神盾局特工
And you're not a S.H.I.E.L.D agent.
她叫什么来着
What was her name again?
雪伦  她很不错的
Sharon. She's nice.
小心点  史蒂夫
Be careful, Steve.
里面的东西你要做好心理准备
You might not want to pull on that thread.
你要去找他吗
You're going after him?
你不必跟我一起来
You don't have to come with me.
我知道  什么时候出发
I know. When do we start?
结束了
It's over.
弗瑞将一切都公之于众了
Fury has released everything to the public.
只公布了他知道的信息
Everything he knows about.
斯托克先生  如果他们知道我们在这里做的事
Mr. Strucker, if they get word of our work here,
如果他们知道我们服务于九头蛇
if they find out we serve Hydra...
九头蛇  神盾局
Hydra, S.H.I.E.L.D,
两个都一样  现在都不行了
two sides of a coin that's no longer currency.
我们拥有的东西  价值是他们无法想象的
What we have is worth more than any of them ever knew.
我们只接触到了点皮毛  就已经...
We've only scratched the surface and already...
世界上还有其他为九头蛇工作的机构
There are other facilities doing Hydra's good work around the world.
全丢给美国队长和他那帮乱七八糟的朋友
We'll feed them to Captain America and his colorful friends.
引开他们的注意
Keep them off our scent.
那些志愿者呢
What about the volunteers?
死了的会被埋得很深
The dead will be buried so deep their own ghosts
谁都不会找到
won't be able to find them.
幸存者呢
And the survivors?
那对双胞胎
The twins.
他们迟早会遇见那对双胞胎
Sooner or later they will meet the twins.
这早已不是间谍的世界了  甚至也不是英雄的世界
It's not a world of spies anymore, not even a world of heroes.
这是属于奇迹的时代  博士
This is the age of miracles, doctor.
没有什么比奇迹更恐怖了
There's nothing more horrifying than a miracle.